Muhammad Wahyu Nugroho Sakti



Software Engineer | Data Analyst | Full-stack Developer

Surabaya, East Java, Indonesia | +62 822-3650-8420 | saktinugraha24@gmail.com

saktinugraha.github.io/ in linkedin.com/in/muhammad-wahyu-nugroho-sakti/

Summary

"Hard Work Never Betray", is my own taught spirit since I was a kid. I started to curious about computer programming at 10th year old when my uncle showed me how to create a clone of the music player in Windows OS. At 16th year old, I start a freelance programmer and start making money from desktop app programming.

Nowadays, my main programming language is Javascript (JS, ES, TS), being a passionate full-stack developer who creates some web or mobile applications using several technologies frameworks such as Express.js, Vue.js, React.js, PHP Laravel, and Java Android, sometimes develop a game using Unity3D as a Hobby. I did some research on artificial intelligence & knowledge discovery in a database for my bachelor's degree and master's degree. Taking knowledge of the data will require a lot of patience, and I really love that, including user behavioral clustering, fraud detection, and anomaly detection. I'm very curious about the newest technology which impactful. Therefore, I studied self-taught for implementation on real problems. During college, I always did remote work and part-time work so I experienced solving real problems. Hence, I did many ways to improve my ability to the latest technology, for example, taking online courses on several platforms. I always believe that impressive communication and hard work never betray

Furthermore, We can discuss if my experience & skill set can help your team/company. Feel free to contact me by email: saktinugraha24@gmail.com or send a message to this LinkedIn profile.

Education

Master of Applied Science, Computer and Informatics Engineering

2018 - now

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya - Indonesia

- Relevant coursework: Advanced Programming, Advance Networking & Security, Web Design & Service Engineering, Artificial Intelligence, Pattern Recognition, Advance Data Science, Knowledge Discovery, Modelling & Simulation, High-Performance Computing,
- Thesis Project: Game Data Science Framework, Clustering Player Behavior Activity and Geospatial Tracking in Game Creative Industry (Express.js, Vue.js, PgSQL, Java)
- Average grade: 3.65/4

Bachelor of Applied Science, Game Technology

2014 - 2018

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya - Indonesia

- Relevant coursework: Algorithm & Programming Concept, Object-oriented Programming, Game Design, Game Mechanics, Network Management, Network & Web Service Programming, Mobile Programming, Multi-player Game Design
- Final Project: Open Analytics Service REST API to collect player activity from digital video game built on top unity3D game engine (Express.js, Vue.js, PgSQL)
- Average grade: 3.72/4

Skill & Competences

- **Programming Language :** Javascript, PHP, Java, Python
- Collaboration Tools: Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Trello, Slack, and Discord
- Engine & Framework: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Vue.js, Laravel, Jersey, Spring, Unity3D
- Performance & Testing Tools:
 Lighthouse, Jest, Cypress, JUnit,
 PHPUnit
- **Development Management :** Waterfall, Scrum, Agile, DevOps

Skill Bar

Javascript

jQuery, Express.js, Vue.js, React.js

PHP

Native, Laravel

Java

Android, Jersey, Spring

Python

Pandas, Scikit-learn, Django

SQL RDBMS

MySQL / MariaDB, PostgreSQL

NoSQL DB

MongoDB, Redis, ElasticSearch

Flastic Universe

Software Engineering

2010 - 2013

SMKN 1 Jenangan Ponorogo (Vocational High School of Engineering)

ElasticSearch, Logstash, Beats, Kibana

Relevant coursework: Desktop Programming, Static Web Page Programming, Dynamic Web Page Programming, Mobile Android Programming, Geographical Information System, Physics, Mathematics, etc

Big Data Environment

Spark, Kafka

Project Experience

Dashboard Picket Schedule Generator (Express.js, Vue.js, 2020 - 2021 MongoDB)

Cloud Environment

Digital Ocean, Heroku, AWS, GCP

PT. Telekomunikasi Indonesia

- Develop a full-stack web application using MEVN stack (Mongo, Express, Vue, Node)
- Lead development team to provide a highly scalable feature to support multi-unit
- Development of boilerplate access control list and authentication using JWT

Version Control System

Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket

Dashboard Rehearsal Test Backbone (Vue.JS)

2020 - 2020

PT. Telekomunikasi Indonesia

• Develop frontend web single-page application using Vue.js

- Integrating client-server connection to REST API using Axios
- Implementation of D3 Chart to presenting real-time event data stream

QA Testing

Jest, Cypress, PHPUnit, JUnit, Unittest

Dashboard Branch Assessment Management System (Laravel, JS)

2020 - 2020

Communication Tools

Telegram, Skype, Trello, Slack, Discord

PT. Telekomunikasi Indonesia

• Develop a full-stack assessment management system to help branch benchmarking

• Make highly customizable module to make the role-based assessment

• Support deployment into test & production server

Development Methodology

Waterfall, Scrum, Agile, DevOps

Dashboard Data Analytics for Ticket Monitoring (Laravel, 2020 - 2020 JS)

PT. Telekomunikasi Indonesia

- Develop full-stack dashboard data analytics to support division service operation
- Create interactive chart dashboard and a table view to scoop reporting
- Scaling the app to help division support expansion

T. Peterromannasi maonesia

Android Apps for Attendance using Al Face Recognition 2019 - 2020

PT. Berdikari Pondasi Perkasa

- Creating android apps for human resource attendance management
- Designing the user interface and micro-interaction
- Make sure that AI face recognition & the algorithm can work in any condition

Customer Ticket Support Web Apps (Laravel, JS)

2019 - 2019

PT. Berkat Inovasi Megah

- Develop a customer support management system using PHP & JS technology
- Develop administrator dashboard & customer dashboard
- Support deployment into test & production server

Backend Blockchain Smart Contract Transaction (Node.js) 2019 - 2019

• Creating backend API for ethereum based blockchain transaction

• Make the backend queue messaging process • Support Deployment into test & production server PowerSign Digital Signage (Express.js, Vue) PT. Magister Sukses Abadi 15

- Designing product of digital signage solution
- Develop a content management system for digital signage dashboard
- Develop serverless architecture to deploy an efficient application

Ahira Hostel Online Room Reservation (LAMP Stack)

2018 - 2018

2019 - 2019

Ahira Group

- Create a landing page & company profile website
- Develop an online booking reservation system
- Develop a content management system using PHP technology

Game Technology Official Website (PHP Wordpress)

2018 - 2018

Game Technology PENS

- Designing an official website of the study program
- Manage and integrating WordPress plugins
- Improving google SEO and web performance by google lighthouse

Front-end Dashboard Web Developer (React, Vue)

2017 - 2017

PT. Ebox Dynamic Solusindo

- Rebuild the functional single page web application from react.js to vue.js with google material design principles
- Integrating front-end web application with REST API
- Responsible to make E2E testing using Cypress

Construction Management Web Apps (LAMP Stack)

2015 - 2015

CV. Budi Surya

- Develop local area network-based web application
- Designing Database management system for budget accounting
- Develop human resources management system

E-commerce Website to Display Research Consulting Project

2014 - 2014

Mulya Riset

- Create a landing page & product grid display
- Develop a content management system using PHP & JS technology
- Support project deployment into production server

E-commerce Website to Display Furniture Product

2013 - 2013

Jatiwangi Furniture

- Create a landing page & product grid display
- Develop a content management system using PHP & JS technology
- Support project deployment into production server

Work Experience

Lead Full-stack Developer (Fulltime)

2017 - Now

Astrocode Space Indonesia

As a lead full-stack developer at Astrocode Indonesia.

Working with several technologies: PHP Laravel, Node.JS Express, VueJS, ReactJS, Java Android.

Responsible to:

- Write code using several programming languages with MVC backend, MVVM web frontend, MVP android, clean code, OOP, and SOLID principles.
- Manage team member of full-stack developer within scrum & agile development methodology
- Make technical decisions in the application development process until the deployment process
- Bridging communication between Project Manager and Client
- Boost apps performance & provide planning to highly scalable performance service

Back-end & Mobile Developer (Express.js, PgSQL) (Internship)

2017 - 2017

PT. Cita Mulia (Parahita Diagnostic Center)

- Recreate REST API using node.js technology & express.js framework
- Integrating REST API with android java
- Designing and create a mobile application for marketing visitation support

Full-stack Web Developer (LAMP Stack) (Remote)

2016 - 2017

PT. Eka Management

- Create End to end web apps solution for managing International labor recruitment.
- Designing MySQL RDBMS for an end to end solution with 3 major application architecture: Recruitment, Finance, and CMS. Creating tons of SQL query.
- Working on both javascript programming at the front-end and native PHP programming at the back-end

Joomla Developer (Internship)

2012 - 2012

PT. Gamatechno Indonesia

As a junior joomla web developer

Responsible to:

- Manage and develop client's website based on Joomla
- Design & create web page
- Provide content news update & Search Engine Optimization

Courses & Certification

Microsoft: DEV280x Building Functional Prototypes using 2019 - 2019 Node.js

edX and Microsoft

- Learn the basics of back-end web development as you create a simple web application server using Node.js.
- Web server basics, HTTP and web routing, SQL, SQLite, and Azure deployment

Microsoft: DFV282x React Router and Redux

2019 - 2019

edX and Microsoft

- Learn how to add routing and state management to your application using React Router and Redux
- Handle routing using React Router, Simplify state management using Redux, and

Google For Business and How to Make a Website

Google and Gapura Digital Surabaya (GDS)

- Build an effective website
- Content and copywriting strategy
- Understanding video branding

React - The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, 2018 - 2018 Redux)

Udemy and Academind

- Build powerful, fast, user-friendly and reactive web apps
- Provide amazing user experiences by leveraging the power of JavaScript with ease
- Learn React Hooks & Class-based Components

NodeJS - The Complete Guide (incl. MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL)

Udemy and Academind

- Understand the NodeJS ecosystem and build server-side rendered apps, REST APIs and GraphQL APIs
- Build modern, fast and scalable server-side web applications with NodeJS, databases like SQL or MongoDB and more

The Entrepreneur Experience

2013 - 2013

Onsite Course by Universitas Ciputra Surabaya

- Learn to make opportunity in entrepreneur skillset
- Personal branding and brand strategy
- Leadership and initiative

Scholarship

Fresh Graduate Scholarship

2018 - 2020

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya

Master graduate scholarship for fresh graduate with cumlaude predicate

Leadership Programme

Community Leader

2015 - 2016

Creative Multimedia Programming Community

- Lead the community to learn new technology in the field of computer science, especially in creative multimedia programming
- Manage community monthly meetup and exhibition support

Team Leader of PYP Team

2013 - 2014

The Entrepreneur Experience by Universitas Ciputra Surabaya

- Lead a software development team to impress instructors with business and computer science skills
- Manage team to develop minimum requirement project to fund

Volunteering Experience

2019 - 2019

N18 ₋ 2018

· with ease

2017 - 2017

- Programming community leader 2015-2016, Programming Is a community in Creative Multimedia Department Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya (PENS), that focuses on the field of learning and sharing about programming language and technology. in this community collaboration and work projects are also implemented with parties from outside the campus.
- PMKS Desktop Apps, together with Ponorogo Youth Programmer, we were developed desktop-based software, it lists people with social welfare problems and then is asked for assistance from the department and the social ministry.
- Ponorogo Youth Programmer, created in 2012. Communities that focus on sharing technology, designing, and develop some projects to make a contribution to the smart government & business in ponorogo regency.

